<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eat. Think. Du.</title>
    <description>Write your site description here. It will be used as your sites meta description as well!</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 17:48:48 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 17:48:48 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Elephant in the Room</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;In Cape Town, I sometimes feel like I&#39;ve been time warped back to pre-civil rights period America.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taken back to a social transition period when women and black people were still in the midst of that transition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which, you know, makes sense, since apartheid ended a mere 20 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am hyper-aware of my biases from previous experiences, my political correctness and sensitivities, but simultaneously acknowledge my lack of knowledge. I am conflicted between being upset about what I’m seeing in Cape Town, yet realizing these problems are not isolated to just this part of the world. These problems also existed and still exist in America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;It&#39;s the elephant in the room. So let&#39;s talk.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of racial separation in Cape Town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From personal experiences, bars and clubs will often either be all white or all black, and social scenes with races intermingling are few and far between. The wait staff at almost every restaurant will be all black, yet the manager will almost always be white. Same goes for a lot of the other jobs in the service industry – construction, housework. Poverty, homelessness, and race seem to be so strongly correlated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are sizeable regions of the city, like the area near the bus station, an entire market above the train station where there is not a single white person to be seen. Race seems to play into people’s sense of security as well, and there seems to be a bit of lingering distrust between pockets of society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While blatantly labelling or grouping people by race is a touchy issue in America, it’s commonly done here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;I&#39;ve felt my own quality of life in Cape Town affected by my race.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basic privileges, like walking on the street or sitting at a restaurant without being called out for being Chinese, become recognized as just that: privileges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been told “Well, you just don’t understand…” and “You see, it’s not like that here…” and “That’s just the way things are right now…” and “That’s not considered racist here…” as explanations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;And I get that. But does that make my thoughts less valid?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cape Town is an incredible place to visit, with a billion of amazing things to offer – beautiful views, beautiful people, a wealth of opportunity, a diverse and fun nightlife, a wealth of mountains and trails perfect for hiking and running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is no denying that there is still a good degree of racism that exists in Cape Town – perhaps mostly because of where we are in its history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;With that being said, it is the mindset of the people that will shape the future of a nation, and only time will tell the social progress that Cape Town, along with the rest of South Africa, can achieve in the coming decades.&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/think/2015/08/14/elephant-in-the-room/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/think/2015/08/14/elephant-in-the-room/</guid>
        
        <category>think</category>
        
        
        <category>think</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Return to China</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;I&#39;m in China!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without even having enough time to process my experience in South Africa, I’m already in Hangzhou, China, a &lt;b&gt;drastically&lt;/b&gt; different environment, participating as a mentor in the MIT China Development Initiative Service Leadership Program. More reflections on Cape Town to come soon, but for now, just wanted to share some first thoughts on coming back to the motherland after 7 years away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;1. The food service here is incredibly fast.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok maybe this is juxtaposed with the service in Cape Town, but it took at least 30 min for a &lt;i&gt;fruit salad&lt;/i&gt; to come in South Africa, and takes less than 10 min for hot bowls of noodles to come in China. You decide which one you prefer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;2. The firewall. That is all.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently unable to access google (WHICH INCLUDES GMAIL) or facebook without a VPN. The result? A frustratingly slow internet connection, gratefulness for the US government, and a first hand understanding as to why China has its own versions of everything (ie Baidu).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;3. The food here really makes me happy.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See adorable steamed custard buns shaped like piggies below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/china/pigs.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding:5px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though this is leading to a problem where I eat all the time and am never hungry, because I’m always eating when I’m already full. Today I felt something that resembled hunger for the first time in 3 days. It promptly left as a shoved some soup dumplings into my mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;4. I STILL GOT IT.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not gonna lie, I was really nervous about my ability to communicate in Mandarin. Since coming here, have been pleasantly surprised by how much I can say with the vocabulary of maybe a 4th grader. Woo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Most of all...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really do feel like I’m &lt;b&gt;coming back&lt;/b&gt; to China, as if I’ve left something, a part of me, behind and it’s been waiting for me all this time. There’s something familiar about the way people behave, about the things that are socially acceptable, about the way people interact with other people, and most of the time, I &lt;b&gt;get&lt;/b&gt; it. Even though I’m generally disconnected from a great deal of Chinese culture, I &lt;b&gt;still&lt;/b&gt; feel connected to the people here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s even stranger for me to think about a parallel universe in which my parents did not immigrate to Minnesota, one in which I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; one of these girls I am mentoring, starry eyed about America, wearing shirts with mismatched English words, eating porridge and watermelon for breakfast and sipping on loose leaf tea instead of my daily cup of coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;One in which this was home, and that&#39;s what I was coming back to.&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/think/2015/08/11/china/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/think/2015/08/11/china/</guid>
        
        <category>think</category>
        
        
        <category>think</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hiking in Cape Town</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;When you think about it, hiking is really just walking.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking on something more rugged than concrete, walking through scenery more nature-filled than a concrete jungle. And when you think of it that way, hiking doesn’t seem all that special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But a big part of what draws me to hiking, and I think a lot of other people as well, aside from the beautiful views and being outside, is the types of conversations I always have with other hikers. Something about spending hours of uninterrupted time with a group of people works magic on bringing out genuine conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Hiking is musing about life and sharing stories -- against a backdrop of mountains, under the pretense of exercise.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though it’s “winter,” I’ve been lucky enough to spend a lot of time hiking here in Cape Town, at least 2-3 times a week. It’s probably my favorite part of this city. Here are the routes I’ve done – grab a friend or two and go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Lion&#39;s Head&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Time: 1.5 hr&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Difficulty: Medium&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Must do hike in Cape Town! Good mix of dirt paths of high incline, steps, rock scrambling, and a short stint ladders/chains. Short enough to go on a lunch break but long enough so it feels like a good workout. Incredible views for a low time investment. Great place to watch the sunset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hike/lions1.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hike/lions2.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Detour off main path near the end of the dirt path to find the caves:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hike/caves1.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hike/caves2.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Table Mountain&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Time: 2 hr up&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Difficulty: Medium&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Platteklip Gorge is a straight-forward route up the mountain consisting of only rock steps probably made for mini giants. That being said, you can take the cable car down for ~R100. Highest, and best view from the top in Cape Town in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hike/table1.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hike/table2.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Skeleton Gorge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Time: 4 hr&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Difficulty: Medium-Hard&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starts at Kirstenbosch Gardens, aka my favorite place in Cape Town, and then go up steps. After a while, you hit ladders and need to scramble over some waterfalls. At the top, you come across a sandy beach and A LAKE. How is that not the perfect hike? Pro-tip: bring food for a picnic in the gardens or at the top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hike/sg1.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hike/sg2.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Tranquility Cracks (Twelve Apostles)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Time: 5 hr&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Difficulty: Easy&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More of a nice nature walk with a little bit of climbing than serious hiking. Starts at the Pipe Track right off of Camps Bay, detour off the path into Tranquility Cracks to explore a mini cave, end back where you started in a loop. Beautiful views with low effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hike/tc1.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hike/tc2.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/du/2015/08/01/hikes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/du/2015/08/01/hikes/</guid>
        
        <category>du</category>
        
        
        <category>du</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>High Tea</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;I generally feel uncomfortable in fancy places.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everytime I go somewhere upscale I feel like I need to pack all of me into a tiny little pretty box, tuck all the ends in, smooth out any edges, and top everything off with a perfect, tidy bow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my mind this box is an easter shade of pastel pink. This bow is made of satin and is white, not off-white.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;This past week, I went to afternoon tea at Mount Nelson Hotel.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Described by Wikipedia as “a social event for the upper classes.” Described by me as an afternoon of unlimited finger foods and bite sized desserts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;And it was actually a &lt;i&gt;ton&lt;/i&gt; of fun.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/tea/finger.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/tea/zerts.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/tea/boys.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/tea/girls.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;I guess there&#39;s an air of &lt;i&gt;innocence&lt;/i&gt; amongst a group of young 20 somethings sitting at high tea.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being excited over saying the word “booking.” Getting to use sugar cubes instead of sugar packets. Spilling 1/2 of a teapot of tea on your pants. Dripping jam on my dress and then trying to subtly lick it off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;I guess there&#39;s also an air of &lt;i&gt;privilege&lt;/i&gt; amongst a group of young 20 somethings sitting at high tea.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left feeling slightly guilty. And it was more than the fact that I literally ate my weight’s worth in clotted cream and jam which was probably going to give me both diabetes and heart disease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here in Cape Town, where the disparity in wealth is so great and so starkly obvious, it made me slightly guilty to know that I could easily and happily spend R270 ($25) on a buffet of tea, finger foods, and mini desserts, while right outside the door the homeless begged for R10 (less than $1) worth of bread. I’ve spent a large portion of my blog talking about the fun things I’ve been able to do, the incredible views I’ve been able to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;But the reality is that there remain a lot of issues that run deep in Cape Town&#39;s veins.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unemployment is a big one. Poverty, and especially poverty in the townships, is another. Race seems to play a huge role in both. At the same time, I’m not naive enough to believe that these issues are specific to Cape Town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From an outsider’s perspective, it sometimes feels like these issues are swept under the facade of a hip, beautiful city trying to prove itself, trying to recover from a not-so-distant, painfully bitter past. Because Cape Town is fairly well developed and resembles a scenic European city by the water, it’s so &lt;b&gt;easy&lt;/b&gt; for tourists to purposefully or accidentally or blissfully ignore the massive disparity in wealth that exists in and around this city. In this country. In this continent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;And to be completely honest, as an American just visiting for a few months, I still don&#39;t know how to respond.&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/eat/2015/07/23/high-tea/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/eat/2015/07/23/high-tea/</guid>
        
        <category>eat</category>
        
        
        <category>eat</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>At the Edge of the World</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Admitting our limits, and that we have limits, is an exercise in humility.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Realizing that humanity itself has limits, and seeing those limits, was that, but at a whole different magnitude. Today, and only for a moment, I looked over a cliff, saw nothing but ocean crashing into mountains melding into sky, and felt like I was seeing the edge of existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were overlooking the water at the southwestern most tip of Africa after having scrambled up some rocks when the thought crossed my mind that the next land mass over was Antarctica and it felt strange to me how the world suddenly seemed so confined. The thought should have been obvious and insignificant, but to me it was neither of those things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our crew headed out early to drive south along a scenic coastline to Cape Point, and lastly, Cape of Good Hope, stopping along some view points along the way. It still surprises me how the mountains never fail to impress me, and that a beautiful sunset or a massive cliff of rocks next to water never gets old. Besides being blessed with incredible T-shirt weather, it was a fun day of exploring, exotic animals, and being impressed by nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/cape/cape1.JPG&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/cape/cape2.JPG&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/cape/cape3.JPG&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/cape/cape4.JPG&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/cape/cape5.JPG&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/cape/cape6.JPG&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/cape/cape7.JPG&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/du/2015/07/19/cape-point/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/du/2015/07/19/cape-point/</guid>
        
        <category>du</category>
        
        
        <category>du</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Garden Route</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;I just had the most incredible weekend.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of friends, of fun, of adventure, memories for a lifetime, being young and being reckless. Feeling close without actually being close, but just enjoying each other’s company and travelling together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a month ago we were just a collection of strangers, but we had stumbled into maybe, probably, definitely too much bonding, and whether we wanted to or not, had become an iX family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weekend was packed with scheduled activities, from visiting caves to riding ostriches, but my favorite moments were the times when we were driving, just staring out the window looking out across the changing landscape the sunset with the mountains and the colors the clouds the trees. Those were the times when the thought crossed my mind that things could not possibly get better than this, that this was perfection and just the act of &lt;b&gt;being&lt;/b&gt; was enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who don’t like to read, I made a video of all the pictures I took. For everyone else, read on for the sparknotes version of the weekend. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OnX0J9it8Uc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Ostrich Riding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/gardenroute/ostrich.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, it might be safe to say that ostriches are probably the dumbest animals known to man. Look at their heads, there is actually physically no room for a brain. Second, ostriches are definitely not meant to be ridden, and it was one of the funniest things to witness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Animal Sanctuary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/gardenroute/cheetah.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though the animal sanctuary was a bit like a glorified zoo, I’m not gonna lie, getting to pet a cheetah was simultaneously so against nature, and also the coolest thing ever. These animals are running, hunting machines. Now domesticated in your nearest South African resrve so that hoards of Americans can snuggle it and snap selfies. Tourism at its finest or most ridiculous?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Backpackers Hostel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/gardenroute/hostel.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our drive up to our hostel by the beach was idealistic like no other, with the sun setting, ocean to our right, and the mist and clouds just hitting the mountains. A bunch of us decided to head to the beach for a night swim, and it really did feel like we were just a bunch of little kids and the beach was our giant sandbox and the ocean was our kiddie pool. The next day we found out a surfer lost his leg to a shark in the &lt;i&gt;next bay over&lt;/i&gt;. Go figure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Rastafarian Community Tour&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/gardenroute/rasta.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Epic trip with an even more epic tour guide (shoutout to brother Zeb). Totally vibing with the culture and the music. Peace, love, and fun grass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Elephant Riding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/gardenroute/elephant.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elephants are just incredibly adorable creatures, and riding off into the sunset with elephants in South Africa held twangs of surrealism, nostalgia, and cheesy tourist vibes. They always look like they’re smiling. Not sure if other animals really compete there. The count of number of animals we rode that weren’t meant to be ridden goes up by 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Bungee Jumping&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/gardenroute/bungee.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So cool I had to write a separate post about it &lt;a href=&quot;/du/2015/06/28/a-216m-leap-of-faith/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Game Drive&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/gardenroute/game.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE&lt;/strong&gt; safari experience, mini edition. We took a open top 4x4 and saw a whole lot of animals. Highlights include perhaps the best tour guide in the world, Leroy, getting close to the lions without dying, and witnessing a carcass recently torn up by a cheetah.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/du/2015/06/29/garden-route/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/du/2015/06/29/garden-route/</guid>
        
        <category>du</category>
        
        
        <category>du</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A 216m Leap of Faith</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;What is your biggest fear?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it dying? Is death the worst thing that can happen to you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be completely honest, I can think of a few things that scare me &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; than death. Losing all your memories and your personality. Losing your mind. Being in a coma and not being able to wake up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not saying I don’t fear death because I do. And heights. Rejection. Loneliness. Failure. I would be lying if I said these things don’t scare me because they &lt;i&gt;absolutely&lt;/i&gt; do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Maybe they even scare you too.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that I’m trying to do with my time off is to face my fears. Usually this leads to me doing questionable or stupid shit, but I think that comes with taking risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think you ever get rid of fear, nor would you want to. That pit in your gut, that flutter in your stomach – those are instincts that keep you alive. It’s not so much about “overcoming” your fears as much as it is about doing despite them, continuing through those moments of uncertainty, the blanched face, the almost-shitting-your-pants, about-to-scream-oh-wait-already-screaming moments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fear is 100% about admitting that you are 100% not ok, so that courage can be the leap of faith that follows. And that faith is the most incredible feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;I took a literal leap of faith today.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A 216m leap to be exact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our group woke up at 7 am to make our 9 am bungee reseravation, and the minute I got off the bus, a hoard of conflicting thoughts were already racing through my brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t want to die.” 
“But I won’t.”
“Trust engineering.”
“Except for those times when engineers fucked up, that’s no good.”
“But wait, this is going to be incredible.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be completely honest, walking from the base to the middle of the bridge was already terrifying. I was walking so slowly I actually apologized to my friend behind me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re up on that ledge, standing, looking over and you just see for miles. In all directions. Including down. Ok so that’s a stretch, but at that moment, you are completely preoccupied with what is happening below, and you can’t help but realize that it’s all trees, valley, which translates to no cushioning if something goes awry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The staff gave me a quick countdown: “3, 2, 1, bungee!” My feet pushed off and I tried to throw my body as far horizontally as I could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;For 2 seconds, my life seemed over.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stomach drops head rush lungs yelling screaming. Well that was dumb. You become instantly aware of how fragile we all are and for a split second you think you’ve made a huge mistake jumping off that bridge because yes you’re going to die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But just as soon as it starts, it’s over. And just as the screaming ends, an amazing rush also takes over and doesn’t let go of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt; The rush is indescribable.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I’m going to do a bad job at explaining it. It’s like a combination of your brain exploding in the best way, having all your senses filled up all at once, and your internal organs having a dance party inside of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;And you are fucking flying.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The laughter started quickly after the jump and didn’t let go of me. I’m not even sure where it stemmed from. But it’s an uncontrollable laughter, laughing because you cheated death and gravity, and because your body doesn’t know how to react besides being thankful that you are safe, so it bursts into a fit of undeniable happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;I was just so grateful to be alive.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Completely amped on life, ready to go out, take on the world, feeling invincible. Best natural high I’ve felt in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;It&#39;s strange to think that all these things were made possible by fear.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not the absence of fear, but the complete presence of fear, and having the complete faith to confront it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/du/2015/06/28/a-216m-leap-of-faith/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/du/2015/06/28/a-216m-leap-of-faith/</guid>
        
        <category>du</category>
        
        
        <category>du</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Old Biscuit Mill</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;If you&#39;ve ever tried to go out to eat with me, you know that I am the worst decider ever.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not that I’m a picky eater. Because I will eat virtually anything and everything in front of me. It’s actually the opposite. Whenever I get a menu, I’m completely overwhelmed by all the choices that &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; potentially make me happy that I get confused about what will make me the &lt;em&gt;happiest&lt;/em&gt;, and end up taking forever to decide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is usually how a typical dinner goes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Look at menu&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Freak out at the first thing that looks good&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Look down the page and realize you get the same feeling looking at half the menu&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enter into life dilemma mode and become extremely focused, debating between at minimum 3 options&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When waiter comes, ask for his or her recommendation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He or she usually says the wrong thing, completely ignore 2-3 recommendations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Order something completely different from original choices and recommendations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ignore friends&#39; exasperated expressions and feel sense of pride for making a decision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;That&#39;s kind of why I love food markets.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can grab tiny things to eat along the way, and get a little bit of everything. No commitment to a large portion, ability to maximize awesomeness. There are a ton of different food markets all over Cape Town, almost every weekend, some of them weekly, some of them seasonal, some of the for special occasions and festivals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Saturday, I went to &lt;b&gt;Old Biscuit Mill&lt;/b&gt; in Woodstock, an artsy neighborhood with chill vibes where hippies, artists, and reggae performers hang.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Old Biscuit Mill had some serious eats -- everything from potato latkes to dim sum to ginger shots...&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/biscuit/market.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Walking through the market
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/biscuit/benedict.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    THE BEST
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/biscuit/mushrooms.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Delicious mushroom kebabs
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/biscuit/paella.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Smells like Spain
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/biscuit/sangria.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Drinks like Spain too
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/biscuit/dimsum.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Taste of Asia?
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/biscuit/bakery.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Artisan bakers
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/biscuit/kosher.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Healthy yums
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;...and also some serious vibes. LIVE MUSIC and a flea market.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GtjP1eWgTlE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;So yes, I &lt;i&gt;still&lt;/i&gt; suck at deciding. Which at Old Biscuit Mill, turned out to be both a blessing and a curse.&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/eat/2015/06/20/old-biscuit-mill/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/eat/2015/06/20/old-biscuit-mill/</guid>
        
        <category>eat</category>
        
        
        <category>eat</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Change of Pace</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;If Cape Town is living a million miles a minute, Stellenbosch is straight up ambling.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stayed behind after the Spice Route tour to spend the weekend with Emily, who is interning in Stellenbosch for the summer. Stellenbosch was definitely a smaller town – not many cars, few people, even fewer beggars. The town seemed predominantly Afrikaans, and it was the first time in South Africa where I was in situations where I couldn’t understand what was going on around me. All in all, it was a well needed break from the fast life with iXperience in Cape Town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Highlights of the trip include:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;beautiful countryside scenery&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;everything was way cheaper. I mean, R5 ice cream, come on&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;better service and an adorably nice waiter at a great steak restaurant&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a real apartment with a real room and a real kitchen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;quiet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;getting to see Emily!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;At the end of the day though, there&#39;s no place I&#39;d rather be than Cape Town :)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/stellenbosch/emily.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Visiting my beautiful little little little twin star Emily!
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/stellenbosch/scenery.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    During our hike.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/stellenbosch/erica.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Happy and grateful for that change in pace.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/du/2015/06/15/change-of-pace/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/du/2015/06/15/change-of-pace/</guid>
        
        <category>du</category>
        
        
        <category>du</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I Have Truly Found Paradise</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;I have truly found paradise.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And not the kind of IHTFP from MIT, none of that. This past weekend we went wine tasting at a gem called Spice Route. Spice Route is basically a collection of artisan food and drink merchants situated on a beautiful farm near Stellenbosch, with awesome chocolate, wine, beer, cheese, biltong, gelato, and art. Did I mention that the chocolate was amazing. Because it was. Seriously the only thing this place is missing to become perfection is puppies. And maybe crepes. I was disappointed that I couldn’t find crepes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started out with a white and red wine tasting, paired with 5 different types of chocolate, and then moved on to beer paired with a biltong and cheese sampler. Even though it’s technically winter here in South Africa, it was really sunny, and the leaves were still falling, kind of like how it would look on a perfect fall day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Here&#39;s a peek into my heaven on earth.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/spice/scenery.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    That background scenery doe, in the midst of beautiful wine country.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/spice/signs.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    All of these things are my favorites.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/spice/path.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Walking through on a beautiful fall day.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/spice/wine.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Wine AND chocolate!
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/spice/chocolate.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Just straight up chocolate.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/spice/biltong_cheese.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Biltong AND cheese!
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/spice/art_barn.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Art barn at the end of the route.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/eat/2015/06/14/ihtfp/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/eat/2015/06/14/ihtfp/</guid>
        
        <category>eat</category>
        
        
        <category>eat</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
