<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eat. Think. Du.</title>
    <description>Write your site description here. It will be used as your sites meta description as well!</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 18:03:56 +0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 18:03:56 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Foodie Paradise</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;The entirety of Singapore is obsessed with eating.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I swear it’s their national past time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides getting to catch up with my cousin (after &lt;b&gt;TWELVE&lt;/b&gt; YEARS!!), the food was the most noteworthy part of my time Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/singapore/ziyue.JPG&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/singapore/ziyuethumbsup.JPG&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;My cousin, Ziyue, and I catching up and being goofs.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Singapore is this highly concentrated mix of cultures, and it inevitably is reflected in the cuisine.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get the most authentic south Indian cuisine in Little India (read: dosas), delicious chicken and rice in Chinatown, and everything you could ever think of in these indoor food markets called “hawker centers” – all for a few dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I had less than 24 hours in Singapore, so I made the most of my time there and did what any foodie would do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;I literally just ate all day. Snapshots below!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/singapore/noodles.JPG&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/singapore/prata.JPG&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/singapore/kacha.JPG&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/singapore/chicken.JPG&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/singapore/dumplings.JPG&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/singapore/dosa.JPG&quot; height=&quot;350px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;First column:&lt;/b&gt; Kway Teow (fried noodles) with fishball soup, Ice Kacang, Fried Sweet Potato Dumplings.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Second column:&lt;/b&gt; Banana Prata, Chicken Rice, Plain Dosa with Curries.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Not pictured:&lt;/b&gt; Kaya Toast, Japanese Katsu Curry&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/eat/2015/08/23/singaporean-eats/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/eat/2015/08/23/singaporean-eats/</guid>
        
        <category>eat</category>
        
        
        <category>eat</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Not Just a Concrete Jungle</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;When I say Hong Kong, do you think of...&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skyscrapers? A huge global financial center? NYC but with millions more asians and they’re all yelling loudly in canto?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok yes, all those are true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hk/city.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hk/market.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;But did you know that a whole other world also exists within hours reach?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When talk of chillin on a secret beach was thrown out during conversation on Friday, I had no idea what to expect. But I figured I liked the words “secret” and “beach,” so any combination of the two &lt;i&gt;had&lt;/i&gt; to be good. I soon discovered that “secret” and “hard to get to” usually went hand in hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Saturday, a crew of us headed out of Hong Kong city by uber (but also accessible by metro/bus) for Sai Kung, a port city in the east. After a ~45 min ride, we hopped on a bus at Sai Kung for another 30 minutes to arrive at a trailhead, as the only way to get to the beach was by foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was hot and sweaty as balls, which is less than optimal hiking weather, but thankfully, the hiking ended up being pretty moderate, and the trail was well-shaded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hk/hike1.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hk/hike2.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a 2 hour hike, we stumbled upon nothing short of paradise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hk/beach3.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hk/beach2.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hk/beach1.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hk/fun.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We headed home around sunset via a different, surprisingly more beautiful hike, which also took around 2 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hk/back1.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hk/back2.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hk/back3.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hk/back4.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a short taxi scare, in which no one had cell service and all taxis were taken, we managed to make friends with a group of canto guys that were also stuck, and hail a taxi…which we then took to the bus stand, only to take a bus to town, only to hail another taxi to get back to the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, round trip time was probably 6 hours. Was that more time than we actually spent at the beach? Maybe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Totally worth it.&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/du/2015/08/23/not-just-a-concrete-jungle/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/du/2015/08/23/not-just-a-concrete-jungle/</guid>
        
        <category>du</category>
        
        
        <category>du</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Spend $5</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;The last time I was in Shanghai, I was 16.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I distinctly remember stepping out of the central train station at night with my family, into a sea of faces that looked too similar to mine, being reluctantly herded forward because we were stuck in a mob. Women were screaming. Children were wailing. I’m pretty sure I cried because I was so upset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;7 years later, I&#39;m so glad I gave Shanghai another shot.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shanghai has become an incredible city with the future and the past coexisting, with sky walkways and tall shiny skyscrapers on one side of the river, and beautifully preserved temples and slightly grungy open air markets on the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/shanghai/mesky.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/shanghai/qibao.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite part though, had to be the food and the quality you could get for almost nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Here&#39;s my guide to eating in Shanghai -- all for under $5.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Bao: $0.50 for 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Bao zi&lt;/i&gt;, or just &lt;i&gt;bao&lt;/i&gt;, are steamed buns with filling on the inside, and are a really popular, traditional Chinese snack or meal. Across 3 days, I tried the veg (left), &lt;i&gt;naidan&lt;/i&gt; (right, essentially a custard made with eggs and milk), red bean, and carrot. All delicious. All $0.25 each. Sold at a little stand right next to where I was staying where they only spoke Shanghainese.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/shanghai/vegbao.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/shanghai/naidan.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Xiao Long Bao: $1.50&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/shanghai/longbao.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Xiao long bao&lt;/i&gt;, or soup dumplings, are probably Shanghai’s trademark dish, and are usually filled with pork and/or shrimp. Also steamed, these dumplings got their name from having a tiny bit of soup packed in with the filling. Probably ate these everyday for a week, so delicious. Ordered these at a “fast food” type of restaurant, meaning it was literally just food served fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Bubble Tea: $1.25&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/shanghai/milktea.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/shanghai/xiaomi.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of coffee, tea is all the rage here, especially milk tea (essentially milk and sugar with a splash of tea). Ever since coming to China, I have successfully drank at least 1 milk tea a day. Instead of just going with the standard boba pearls, you can get all sorts of other toppings inside, like &lt;i&gt;sanxiongdi&lt;/i&gt; (tapioca pearls, pudding, grass jelly) or &lt;i&gt;xiaomi&lt;/i&gt; (basically mini tapioca pearls). Low key obsessed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Noodles: $1.25&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/shanghai/noodles.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full confession: my Chinese reading ability is existent, but not that good. I walked into a noodle shop where the menu was all in Chinese and ordered the first thing I could read – noodles with egg and vegetables. Got lucky, the noodles happened to be handmade, soup was delicious.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/eat/2015/08/20/eating-in-shanghai/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/eat/2015/08/20/eating-in-shanghai/</guid>
        
        <category>eat</category>
        
        
        <category>eat</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Final Words</title>
        <description>&lt;h3&gt;Bru, did I have the adventure of a lifetime.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&quot;/du/2015/06/28/a-216m-leap-of-faith/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bungee jumped&lt;/a&gt; off a 216 m bridge, and dove in a cage with &lt;a href=&quot;/du/2015/06/07/unreal-reality/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;great whites&lt;/a&gt;. I pet not one, but two &lt;a href=&quot;/du/2015/06/29/garden-route/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;cheetahs&lt;/a&gt; simultaneously. I rode an ostrich until I fell off, and an elephant until the sun set. I took selfies with penguins at the end of the world, and got photos taken of me on a sandboard against crystal blue skies and perfect white sand dunes. I was beaten down by countless waves until I stood up on a surfboard, and beat down countless drinks until I couldn’t stand. I &lt;a href=&quot;/du/2015/08/01/hikes/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;hiked&lt;/a&gt; mountains to happen upon lakes, and ran alongside the ocean to get a glimpse of the mountains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alongside an awesome teaching staff, I helped 73 students learn how to code in a matter of months, and helped them build beautiful, functional web apps that tackled problems from food waste all the way to education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;But Jesus, did I &lt;i&gt;struggle&lt;/i&gt; like I have never before.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was plenty of social drama the first couple of months, which felt like I was living in a reality TV show, complete with my own plot line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had trouble with work, not the work itself, but the conditions I agreed to. I thought about quitting. At times I felt I made the wrong choice deciding to come work for iX, like they had found the wrong person to TA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My professional life and personal life melded together into this goopy mess, as I lived with, worked with, and partied with the same group of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sometimes felt stuck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Some people call struggle by another name. I personally quite like &quot;growth.&quot;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through it all, I learned about the power of &lt;b&gt;surrounding myself with people who saw me for who I &lt;i&gt;could&lt;/i&gt; be&lt;/b&gt;. Especially a Zulu Queen, a programmer turned technology educator, and a new coder with a thousand lives. Nothing was more motivating than people by my side genuinely advocating for my success, and weren’t afraid to tell me straight when I could do better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I could &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began to think hard about living life the way you &lt;b&gt;choose&lt;/b&gt; to live it, and what it means to design your lifestyle. I learned that it starts with just that – a conscious choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What really made my experience, though, were my students.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bunch of &lt;b&gt;strangers&lt;/b&gt;, who came from all over the world to be &lt;b&gt;students&lt;/b&gt;, who I soon called my &lt;b&gt;friends&lt;/b&gt;, who slowly became my &lt;b&gt;family&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were the ones who threw me the most badass birthday parties I’ve ever had, and forced me to live in the moment, if only for a moment. They were the ones who shared their life stories with me, and saw &lt;i&gt;me&lt;/i&gt; at my realest, the ones who saw through all sorts of bullshit, and called me out on mine. They were the ones who’s passion for what they were doing renewed my passion for what I was doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not the place I loved and it’s not the place I’ll miss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;It&#39;s the people I had the opportunity to meet along the way, &lt;i&gt;these people&lt;/i&gt;. The ones I came to teach, but who became the ones who taught me the most about myself.&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/think/2015/08/16/reflecting-on-cape-town/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/think/2015/08/16/reflecting-on-cape-town/</guid>
        
        <category>think</category>
        
        
        <category>think</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thoughts on Race</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;In Cape Town, I sometimes feel like I&#39;ve been time warped back to pre-civil rights period America.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taken back to a social transition period when women and black people were still in the midst of that transition. Which, you know, makes sense, since apartheid ended a mere 20 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the stuff I’ve noticed is pretty innocent, some confusing, a few questionable. A handful that left an impression on me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like that time I didn’t see any white Capetonians taking the train. Actually, to be honest, didn’t see any non-black Capetonians in the entire vicinity of the train station, including this massive market above it. Or that time when the entire wait staff at a cafe tried to speak “Chinese” to me when I asked for water. Would later receive a verbal apology by manager. Then there was that South African legislator, who didn’t believe I was actually from America. So the follow-up question to “where are you from?” was naturally “no, but where are you &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; from?” I get this response &lt;b&gt;a lot&lt;/b&gt; when I travel, but for some reason was surprised when he asked me that. Maybe it’s because I’ve never been asked that from someone whose first language is English. And you know, is educated and writes laws for a living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are the things that happen on a regular basis like walking into my favorite bar, and realizing that I’m the only non-white person in the entire place. I somehow became hyper-aware of this fact and quickly realized that this all-black or all-white situation was the case with &lt;b&gt;a lot&lt;/b&gt; of the social scene in Cape Town. Or the fact that every construction worker, house worker, and parking attendant I passed was a black man working for a white family. All the wait staff of every restaurant on the street I lived on were black, managed by a white manager. Believe this is because of something called Black Economic Empowerment but could be wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There generally seems to be the sentiment that even though this isn’t the way things should be, it’s just the way it is right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d be naive to think that other countries, including America, don’t struggle with race, because they absolutely do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The truth is that 20 years is a blink of an eye in the span of history, and only time will tell the social progress that Cape Town, along with the rest of South Africa, can achieve in the coming decades.&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/think/2015/08/14/thoughts-on-race/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/think/2015/08/14/thoughts-on-race/</guid>
        
        <category>think</category>
        
        
        <category>think</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Return to China</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;I&#39;m in China!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without even having enough time to process my experience in South Africa, I’m already in Hangzhou, China, a &lt;b&gt;drastically&lt;/b&gt; different environment, participating as a mentor in the MIT China Development Initiative Service Leadership Program. More reflections on Cape Town to come soon, but for now, just wanted to share some first thoughts on coming back to the motherland after 7 years away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;1. The food service here is incredibly fast.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok maybe this is juxtaposed with the service in Cape Town, but it took at least 30 min for a &lt;i&gt;fruit salad&lt;/i&gt; to come in South Africa, and takes less than 10 min for hot bowls of noodles to come in China. You decide which one you prefer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;2. The firewall. That is all.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently unable to access google (WHICH INCLUDES GMAIL) or facebook without a VPN. The result? A frustratingly slow internet connection, gratefulness for the US government, and a first hand understanding as to why China has its own versions of everything (ie Baidu).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;3. The food here really makes me happy.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See adorable steamed custard buns shaped like piggies below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/china/pigs.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding:5px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though this is leading to a problem where I eat all the time and am never hungry, because I’m always eating when I’m already full. Today I felt something that resembled hunger for the first time in 3 days. It promptly left as a shoved some soup dumplings into my mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;4. I STILL GOT IT.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not gonna lie, I was really nervous about my ability to communicate in Mandarin. Since coming here, have been pleasantly surprised by how much I can say with the vocabulary of maybe a 4th grader. Woo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Most of all...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really do feel like I’m &lt;b&gt;coming back&lt;/b&gt; to China, as if I’ve left something, a part of me, behind and it’s been waiting for me all this time. There’s something familiar about the way people behave, about the things that are socially acceptable, about the way people interact with other people, and most of the time, I &lt;b&gt;get&lt;/b&gt; it. Even though I’m generally disconnected from a great deal of Chinese culture, I &lt;b&gt;still&lt;/b&gt; feel connected to the people here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s even stranger for me to think about a parallel universe in which my parents did not immigrate to Minnesota, one in which I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; one of these girls I am mentoring, starry eyed about America, wearing shirts with mismatched English words, eating porridge and watermelon for breakfast and sipping on loose leaf tea instead of my daily cup of coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;One in which this was home, and that&#39;s what I was coming back to.&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/think/2015/08/11/china/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/think/2015/08/11/china/</guid>
        
        <category>think</category>
        
        
        <category>think</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hiking in Cape Town</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;When you think about it, hiking is really just walking.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking on something more rugged than concrete, walking through scenery more nature-filled than a concrete jungle. And when you think of it that way, hiking doesn’t seem all that special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But a big part of what draws me to hiking, and I think a lot of other people as well, aside from the beautiful views and being outside, is the types of conversations I always have with other hikers. Something about spending hours of uninterrupted time with a group of people works magic on bringing out genuine conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Hiking is musing about life and sharing stories -- against a backdrop of mountains, under the pretense of exercise.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though it’s “winter,” I’ve been lucky enough to spend a lot of time hiking here in Cape Town, at least 2-3 times a week. It’s probably my favorite part of this city. Here are the routes I’ve done – grab a friend or two and go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Lion&#39;s Head&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Time: 1.5 hr&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Difficulty: Medium&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Must do hike in Cape Town! Good mix of dirt paths of high incline, steps, rock scrambling, and a short stint ladders/chains. Short enough to go on a lunch break but long enough so it feels like a good workout. Incredible views for a low time investment. Great place to watch the sunset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hike/lions1.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hike/lions2.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Detour off main path near the end of the dirt path to find the caves:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hike/caves1.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hike/caves2.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Table Mountain&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Time: 2 hr up&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Difficulty: Medium&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Platteklip Gorge is a straight-forward route up the mountain consisting of only rock steps probably made for mini giants. That being said, you can take the cable car down for ~R100. Highest, and best view from the top in Cape Town in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hike/table1.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hike/table2.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Skeleton Gorge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Time: 4 hr&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Difficulty: Medium-Hard&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starts at Kirstenbosch Gardens, aka my favorite place in Cape Town, and then go up steps. After a while, you hit ladders and need to scramble over some waterfalls. At the top, you come across a sandy beach and A LAKE. How is that not the perfect hike? Pro-tip: bring food for a picnic in the gardens or at the top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hike/sg1.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hike/sg2.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Tranquility Cracks (Twelve Apostles)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Time: 5 hr&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Difficulty: Easy&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More of a nice nature walk with a little bit of climbing than serious hiking. Starts at the Pipe Track right off of Camps Bay, detour off the path into Tranquility Cracks to explore a mini cave, end back where you started in a loop. Beautiful views with low effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hike/tc1.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/hike/tc2.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;350px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/du/2015/08/01/hikes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/du/2015/08/01/hikes/</guid>
        
        <category>du</category>
        
        
        <category>du</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>High Tea</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;I generally feel uncomfortable in fancy places.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everytime I go somewhere upscale I feel like I need to pack all of me into a tiny little pretty box, tuck all the ends in, smooth out any edges, and top everything off with a perfect, tidy bow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my mind this box is an easter shade of pastel pink. This bow is made of satin and is white, not off-white.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;This past week, I went to afternoon tea at Mount Nelson Hotel.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Described by Wikipedia as “a social event for the upper classes.” Described by me as an afternoon of unlimited finger foods and bite sized desserts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;And it was actually a &lt;i&gt;ton&lt;/i&gt; of fun.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/tea/finger.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/tea/zerts.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/tea/boys.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/tea/girls.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;I guess there&#39;s an air of &lt;i&gt;innocence&lt;/i&gt; amongst a group of young 20 somethings sitting at high tea.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being excited over saying the word “booking.” Getting to use sugar cubes instead of sugar packets. Spilling 1/2 of a teapot of tea on your pants. Dripping jam on my dress and then trying to subtly lick it off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;I guess there&#39;s also an air of &lt;i&gt;privilege&lt;/i&gt; amongst a group of young 20 somethings sitting at high tea.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left feeling slightly guilty. And it was more than the fact that I literally ate my weight’s worth in clotted cream and jam which was probably going to give me both diabetes and heart disease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here in Cape Town, where the disparity in wealth is so great and so starkly obvious, it made me slightly guilty to know that I could easily and happily spend R270 ($25) on a buffet of tea, finger foods, and mini desserts, while right outside the door the homeless begged for R10 (less than $1) worth of bread. I’ve spent a large portion of my blog talking about the fun things I’ve been able to do, the incredible views I’ve been able to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;But the reality is that there remain a lot of issues that run deep in Cape Town&#39;s veins.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unemployment is a big one. Poverty, and especially poverty in the townships, is another. Race seems to play a huge role in both. At the same time, I’m not naive enough to believe that these issues are specific to Cape Town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From an outsider’s perspective, it sometimes feels like these issues are swept under the facade of a hip, beautiful city trying to prove itself, trying to recover from a not-so-distant, painfully bitter past. Because Cape Town is fairly well developed and resembles a scenic European city by the water, it’s so &lt;b&gt;easy&lt;/b&gt; for tourists to purposefully or accidentally or blissfully ignore the massive disparity in wealth that exists in and around this city. In this country. In this continent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;And to be completely honest, as an American just visiting for a few months, I still don&#39;t know how to respond.&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/eat/2015/07/23/high-tea/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/eat/2015/07/23/high-tea/</guid>
        
        <category>eat</category>
        
        
        <category>eat</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>At the Edge of the World</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Admitting our limits, and that we have limits, is an exercise in humility.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Realizing that humanity itself has limits, and seeing those limits, was that, but at a whole different magnitude. Today, and only for a moment, I looked over a cliff, saw nothing but ocean crashing into mountains melding into sky, and felt like I was seeing the edge of existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were overlooking the water at the southwestern most tip of Africa after having scrambled up some rocks when the thought crossed my mind that the next land mass over was Antarctica and it felt strange to me how the world suddenly seemed so confined. The thought should have been obvious and insignificant, but to me it was neither of those things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our crew headed out early to drive south along a scenic coastline to Cape Point, and lastly, Cape of Good Hope, stopping along some view points along the way. It still surprises me how the mountains never fail to impress me, and that a beautiful sunset or a massive cliff of rocks next to water never gets old. Besides being blessed with incredible T-shirt weather, it was a fun day of exploring, exotic animals, and being impressed by nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/cape/cape1.JPG&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/cape/cape2.JPG&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/cape/cape3.JPG&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/cape/cape4.JPG&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/cape/cape5.JPG&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/cape/cape6.JPG&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/cape/cape7.JPG&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/du/2015/07/19/cape-point/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/du/2015/07/19/cape-point/</guid>
        
        <category>du</category>
        
        
        <category>du</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Garden Route</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;I just had the most incredible weekend.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of friends, of fun, of adventure, memories for a lifetime, being young and being reckless. Feeling close without actually being close, but just enjoying each other’s company and travelling together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a month ago we were just a collection of strangers, but we had stumbled into maybe, probably, definitely too much bonding, and whether we wanted to or not, had become an iX family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weekend was packed with scheduled activities, from visiting caves to riding ostriches, but my favorite moments were the times when we were driving, just staring out the window looking out across the changing landscape the sunset with the mountains and the colors the clouds the trees. Those were the times when the thought crossed my mind that things could not possibly get better than this, that this was perfection and just the act of &lt;b&gt;being&lt;/b&gt; was enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who don’t like to read, I made a video of all the pictures I took. For everyone else, read on for the sparknotes version of the weekend. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OnX0J9it8Uc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Ostrich Riding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/gardenroute/ostrich.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, it might be safe to say that ostriches are probably the dumbest animals known to man. Look at their heads, there is actually physically no room for a brain. Second, ostriches are definitely not meant to be ridden, and it was one of the funniest things to witness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Animal Sanctuary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/gardenroute/cheetah.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though the animal sanctuary was a bit like a glorified zoo, I’m not gonna lie, getting to pet a cheetah was simultaneously so against nature, and also the coolest thing ever. These animals are running, hunting machines. Now domesticated in your nearest South African resrve so that hoards of Americans can snuggle it and snap selfies. Tourism at its finest or most ridiculous?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Backpackers Hostel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/gardenroute/hostel.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our drive up to our hostel by the beach was idealistic like no other, with the sun setting, ocean to our right, and the mist and clouds just hitting the mountains. A bunch of us decided to head to the beach for a night swim, and it really did feel like we were just a bunch of little kids and the beach was our giant sandbox and the ocean was our kiddie pool. The next day we found out a surfer lost his leg to a shark in the &lt;i&gt;next bay over&lt;/i&gt;. Go figure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Rastafarian Community Tour&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/gardenroute/rasta.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Epic trip with an even more epic tour guide (shoutout to brother Zeb). Totally vibing with the culture and the music. Peace, love, and fun grass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Elephant Riding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/gardenroute/elephant.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elephants are just incredibly adorable creatures, and riding off into the sunset with elephants in South Africa held twangs of surrealism, nostalgia, and cheesy tourist vibes. They always look like they’re smiling. Not sure if other animals really compete there. The count of number of animals we rode that weren’t meant to be ridden goes up by 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Bungee Jumping&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/gardenroute/bungee.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So cool I had to write a separate post about it &lt;a href=&quot;/du/2015/06/28/a-216m-leap-of-faith/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Game Drive&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/gardenroute/game.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE&lt;/strong&gt; safari experience, mini edition. We took a open top 4x4 and saw a whole lot of animals. Highlights include perhaps the best tour guide in the world, Leroy, getting close to the lions without dying, and witnessing a carcass recently torn up by a cheetah.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/du/2015/06/29/garden-route/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/du/2015/06/29/garden-route/</guid>
        
        <category>du</category>
        
        
        <category>du</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
