<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eat. Think. Du.</title>
    <description>Write your site description here. It will be used as your sites meta description as well!</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 23:21:02 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 23:21:02 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>You in Southeast Asia</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Coming soon!&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/du/2015/12/02/itinerary/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/du/2015/12/02/itinerary/</guid>
        
        <category>du</category>
        
        
        <category>du</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>You in Southeast Asia</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;First, congrats!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s still uncommon for Americans to forgo the classic “Eurotrip” for that part of the world we either learn about in history books, hear about from grandparents talking about their “time back in ‘nam,” or see from those cheesy travel instagrams that we all know are staged but not-so-secretly envy anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Second, get excited because Southeast Asia is just as fucking incredible as everyone says.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these buzzwords - “freedom,” “adventure” - that mean absolutely nothing on their own will mean something to you. They will mean having to use every language you know and some that you don’t to get back home after dark because transportation doesn’t work like they should. They will mean trusting locals more than you do google maps, and ignoring 80% of advice from books and blogs (probably including this one).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Because a lot of people have been asking me, this post will cover practical advice and suggestions for those hoping or planning to go to Southeast Asia.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;I will also post &lt;a href=&quot;/du/2015/12/02/itinerary/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;my itinerary&lt;/a&gt; for reference.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you guys find this useful in some way, and if you do end up going to Southeast Asia, I’d love to hear about it :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Advice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;1. Don&#39;t plan too much.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first started backpacking, I was a girl prepared. I knew where I was staying. I knew generally what there was to do in each place. I read Hostelworld reviews and Trip Advisor forums. Within a week, I stopped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time I got to Vietnam, I would show up to a hostel on a fellow traveler’s recommendation, ask if there were any beds available and then head out to explore. I would then leave if I was 1) bored and I wanted to check out another city, 2) my visa was expiring and I had to book it out of the country 3) adjusting my travel plans to spend more time with people I met along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I liked travelling like this, but always knew my options so was flexible enough to choose my own destiny, but always had enough plans to not let passiveness take over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll have to find a balance for what you feel comfortable with and what works for you, but I’d challenge you to be more spontaneous than you usually are. You never know who you might meet, which cities you’ll fall in love with, where you feel like you could spend an eternity. &lt;b&gt;Don’t pre-limit yourself!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;2. Ask like-minded travellers for advice.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be prepared to have the same conversation literally over and over again. It’s like freshman orientation in that everyone says the same facts about themselves except the stopping point is when you stop travelling. You’ll be asked where you’re from. How long you’ve been travelling. Where you’ve been. Where you’re going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Take this time to ask for tips!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But don’t follow every piece of advice you get. Figure out if you guys have similar interests/vibes and then go from there. In Vietnam, talking to lots of outdoorsy, active people led me to Dalat, Phong Nha, and Sa Pa, 3 of my favorite places in all of Southeast Asia, and caused me to skip over some other cities on the backpackers trail. In addition to asking for things to do, ask for where to stay. Again, gauge the advice based on vibe and if you like them. There are party hostels where you can play as much beer pong as your inner college frat boy desires, and there are swanky, how-is-this-only-$15 hostels for swankier folk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally liked the homestay type hostels the best, but have definitely stayed in a spectrum. It took me a while to get the hang of taking advice from the right people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;3. Go solo.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When do you do things alone? And not like “shower” and “cook dinner.” I mean like real world things like go to a restaurant or a movie. If the answer to that is never, than you and I are in the same boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travelling alone might not make too much sense at first. I’ve gotten a spectrum of questions. Why do you need to cross half the world to be by yourself? You can do that kind of stuff, you know, anywhere. Isn’t it scary? Didn’t you get lonely?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To answer those questions, 1. no, I actually never got lonely, 2. sometimes did get scared but never felt “in danger,” and 3. there’s a volume and variety of activity you experience while travelling that is so incomparable to regular life, that being by yourself is a completely different experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You gain an impressive amount of skills when travelling alone since you’re doing so many new things by yourself at such a high frequency. You have to figure out what &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt; actually want on a daily basis, and actively &lt;i&gt;choose&lt;/i&gt; who to spend time with. Above all, you’ll gain an increased sense of self and confidence in your own abilities. That sense of empowerment isn’t something that disappears when you come back to America - that shit sticks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;4. General food advice.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eat street food, but only where the locals are lining up. Good rule of thumb, if you see locals eating there, it’s good. If you see tons of locals, it’s probably really fucking good. If you see no locals, but do see tourists, it’s probably good but wayyyy overpriced. If you see literally no one, don’t eat the food. If you can’t read the sign, don’t let that stop you! Point and pay. That’s pretty universal. (pro-tip Saigon is an awesome city to just walk around and buy street food)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buy bottled water, just do it. The largest bottle you can without being obnoxious. Hostels will rip you off so try to buy everything at stores, you should be able to get a huge bottle of water for less than $1 everywhere you go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Raw veg is iffy. Vietnamese food has a ton of raw herbs so be careful, but you don’t necessarily need to avoid it altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the food in Sapa, Vietnam is literal shit. Not sure why. Do not get the fixed menu deals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;5. Other general advice.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Keep a travel journal.&lt;/b&gt; I have bits of writing here and there but met people with extensive records and was jealous. One girl I met was following her grandpa’s backpacking trip off his journal from way back when. Life goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Try to bring ca$h and not use ATMs, those fees rack up.&lt;/b&gt; In Cambodia, everyone actualy uses $1 bills, so stock up on singles. Otherwise get $100s and bring them with you to exchange money. To give a upper-bound estimate, food will run you $3-5 a meal, accommodation $5-8, $1-2/beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rent a motorbike/moped, just don’t go too crazy.&lt;/b&gt; You’ll see a lot of people get injured and bandaged, it happens. Find a place without too many bikes on the road (like an island), get someone to take time and teach you how to ride it, take a few practice laps first, and wear a helmet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pack as light as possible.&lt;/b&gt; I was working 13 kg - which included my laptop and DSLR. If anything, I would’ve invested in some good hiking shoes, walking shoes, and flip flops.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/think/2015/12/02/guide/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/think/2015/12/02/guide/</guid>
        
        <category>think</category>
        
        
        <category>think</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thailand Highlights</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Compared to Vietnam and Cambodia, Thailand was shockingly easy.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I almost wish I started my trip here, as a more gentle introduction to the backpacking life. It surprised me how developed cities were, from infrastructure to amenities to home comforts like fast food and 711 and Oreos. Everyone spoke English (and spoke it well), activities were just laid out for travellers, street food was located at the most convenient corners, hostels were basically set up for backpackers to hang out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Although significantly more tourist-y, there was so so so much to do in Thailand.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My 18 days in &lt;b&gt;no way&lt;/b&gt; did it justice. In the north of Thailand I went wilderness trekking, temple hopped, rode my scooter through valleys of unreal scenery, befriended elephants - not to mention everything was dirt cheap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the south of Thailand I spent days just sipping on young coconuts chillin on postcard worthy beaches, got scuba certified in sky blue waters, watched fire dancers spin at night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not even mentioning Bangkok. And all that is, well, Bangkok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What colored my time in Thailand was the group of backpackers I was lucky enough to travel with for part of my trip.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over just a couple of days, our group of backpackers from Chiang Mai became a “squad.” A squad that made moving from place to place less strange, more welcoming, and always fun. A mini travel family that looked out for each other and stuck together - even when my own travel schedule was off everyone else’s by a few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like any family trip, yes, it took forever to mobilize and get places. Deciding on a restaurant was a true mission. But no matter what, in whichever city, we would always make the effort to spend time together. They were the people who could easily bypass the small talk and get straight to the realtalk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;So here&#39;s a shoutout to my #SQUAD. You guys made me think. You guys made me laugh. Stay gold.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/thailand/squad.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Other Highlights&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/thailand/scuba.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px;width:600px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Getting SSI Open Water certified in Koh Tao.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/thailand/scooter.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px;width:600px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mopeding in Pai.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/think/2015/10/13/thailand/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/think/2015/10/13/thailand/</guid>
        
        <category>think</category>
        
        
        <category>think</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Homage to Thai Food</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;When it comes to Southeast Asian cuisine, Thailand is the clear winner, hands-down, not even a competition.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, Thailand has pretty kick-ass food. Plentiful coconut milk, palm sugar, throw in a little bit of spice and everything nice - maybe basil, garlic, tumeric. I even took a day-long cooking course in order to try my hand at some of the more popular dishes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/thailand/serious.JPG&quot; height=&quot;375px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/thailand/me.JPG&quot; height=&quot;375px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Intense focus making curry powder, followed by a successful pad thai.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/thailand/spices.JPG&quot; width=&quot;500px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Basketful of goodness procured by our cooking instructor.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the same strain of flavors bringing everything together, you really can’t go wrong. Curries, pad thais, fried noodles, sticky rice, papaya salads, refreshing mango shakes. Obtained from the most unassuming of wooden stands off the side of the road, always made by adorable old Thai men and women. I could go on forever (and eat forever) but I don’t want you guys to get bored, and I also don’t want to come home obese.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Photo Homage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/thailand/papaya.JPG&quot; width=&quot;450px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px;width:600px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Papaya Salad: crunchy with a bit of a kick, a touch of sweet, topped with roasted peanuts&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/thailand/springroll.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;450px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px;width:600px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Spring Rolls: crispy, flaky, stuffed with goodness then dipped in a sweet chili sauce&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/thailand/pt.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;450px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Pad Thai: the classic, quick, fast, easy, cheap, delicious&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/thailand/pse.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;450px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px;width:600px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Pad See Ew: thick, fat, fried noodles sauteed with veg so you can pretend it&#39;s healthy&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/thailand/green.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;450px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px;width:600px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Chicken Green Curry: two types of eggplant and beans soaked in a coconut milk based curry&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/thailand/panang.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;450px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Chicken Panang Curry: no idea what&#39;s in this, but it&#39;s delicious&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/thailand/tea.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;450px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px;width:600px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Thai Iced Tea: the Vietnamese coffee of Thailand, black tea with condensed milk&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/eat/thailand/msr.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;450px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px;width:600px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mango Sticky Rice: most genius combo known to man = mango + sticky rice + coconut milk + roasted mung bean&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/eat/2015/10/11/thai-food/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/eat/2015/10/11/thai-food/</guid>
        
        <category>eat</category>
        
        
        <category>eat</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Elephant Jungle Sanctuary</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;To me, elephants always seemed invincible.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’re smart. They’re adorable. They’re massive yet friendly. They’re exotic. Everyone, and I mean everyone, can’t help but fall in love with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/thailand/elephants/smile.JPG&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It came as a huge shock to me that the majority of elephants in Thailand are actually &lt;i&gt;suffering&lt;/i&gt; working in the tourism industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;My day visiting the Elephant Jungle Sanctuary was both a fun, and eye-opening experience.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a 2 hour drive and a bit of bumpy off-roading through a jungle in our tuk-tuk red cab, the trees opened up into what I can only describe as &lt;b&gt;elephant paradise&lt;/b&gt; - lush green grass, rolling hills, a pile of corn husks, a mud pool, and a waterfall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, along with the rest of the group, changed into traditional &lt;i&gt;mahout&lt;/i&gt; gear, a colorful rug-like t-shirt we were to wear for the rest of our time at Elephant Jungle Sanctuary, and were given a brief introduction of their mission, and also background on the plight of the Asian Elephant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/thailand/elephants/elephant.jpg&quot; height=&quot;375px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Because of agriculture and human expansion, there is no longer room for the wild Asian elephant.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elephants in captivity have &lt;i&gt;mahouts&lt;/i&gt;, the name for elephant caretakers, but they sometimes do not give their elephants the best care out of desperation for money or just lack of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m talking broken or disfigured backs from elephant riding, emotional abuse from a young age, exhaustion from being overworked. They are chained, fenced in, poked and prodded with wooden hooks in order to follow human commands sheerly for the purpose of tourist entertainment. The oldest elephant at Elephant Jungle Sanctuary actually had a crooked back from riding years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethically responsible elephant parks, like Elephant Jungle Sanctuary and Elephant Nature Park, take in formerly abused elephants, take care of them, and allow them to roam free within the sanctuaries - without chains, hooks, or riding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/thailand/elephants/tree.JPG&quot; height=&quot;375px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/thailand/elephants/closeup.JPG&quot; height=&quot;375px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;We still spent the entire day interacting with elephants - but in a way that was safe and enjoyable for both the animals and for visitors.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We fed the elephants bunches of bananas (they literally do not stop eating and pooping), walked with them around the grounds, played with them in the mud pits, and lastly bathed them in the waterfall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/thailand/elephants/big.JPG&quot; height=&quot;375px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/thailand/elephants/morebath.jpg&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of which felt more &lt;b&gt;natural&lt;/b&gt; than riding, and allowed you to get close to the massive creatures in a way that seemed &lt;b&gt;comfortable&lt;/b&gt;. Seeing how smart, friendly, and hilarious elephants are, so up close and personal was not only an incredible experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/thailand/elephants/baby.JPG&quot; height=&quot;375px&quot; width=&quot;336px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/thailand/elephants/kisses.jpg&quot; width=&quot;413px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;It was also a lesson on humanity, on our effect on the creatures around us, and a challenge to look a little deeper when participating in animal tourism.&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/du/2015/10/04/elephant-jungle-sanctuary/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/du/2015/10/04/elephant-jungle-sanctuary/</guid>
        
        <category>du</category>
        
        
        <category>du</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Vietnam: Part II</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;I hate to play favorites, but the north of Vietnam was the best.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My last 10 days consisted mostly of trekking, exploring, visiting quirky joints, and being surrounded by awe-inspring nature. Everything I ever wanted but didn’t expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Phong Nha&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hands down my favorite spot in Vietnam. Backpackers come to Phong Nha for one thing and one thing only - caving in the national park. As a result, there is just one backpacker&#39;s hostel, Easy Tiger, in a small makeshift town with just a couple of restaurants, cafes, and bars. In total, our group visited 4 caves across 2 days, each unique and worthwhile for different reasons. The Paradise Cave stuck out for its sheer size and structural beauty, but the Dark Cave was my favorite just for the adventure experience of kayaking, ziplining, swimming, and trodding through a mud pit. Besides caving, Phong Nha is home to Pub with the Cold Beer, where customers can catch and kill their own chicken, and then eat it immediately. Quite possibly the best chicken dinner I&#39;ve had in my entire life, with cold beer (as promised) and hammocks to boot. Easy Tiger itself was an awesome hub, with live music almost every night. Take me back?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/parttwo/boat.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/parttwo/cave.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/parttwo/opening.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/parttwo/pub.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Cat Ba Island&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of taking the infamous $200+ Ha Long Bay booze cruise from Hanoi, I opted to take a 1 day Ha Long Bay tour from Cat Ba for $20. Weather was teetering between perfect and sprinkly, which was less than ideal, but we still had an awesome time cruising, swimming, snorkelling, kayaking, and just chilling on a boat together. I also learned how to &lt;a href=&quot;/think/2015/09/22/best-of-vietnam/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;moped!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/parttwo/fishing.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/parttwo/island.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/parttwo/kayak.jpg&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/parttwo/moto.jpg&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Sa Pa&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, breathtaking and surreal. I’ll let the pictures speak for themselves. We spent 1 full day trekking from town to a homestay in a Hmong village. We walked through jungle, down lush rice paddies, across a river. If that sounded like a Dora the Explorer episode, that’s because it still blows my mind that a place that stunning exists in real life, and that people live there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/parttwo/valley.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/parttwo/clouds.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/parttwo/paddies.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/parttwo/layer.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Hanoi&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Literally spent maybe 4 waking hours in Hanoi, which I concluded was actually crazier than Saigon. Was caught in a lot of rain, and running short on time, so wasn’t able to do as much exploring as I would’ve liked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/parttwo/roundabout.jpg&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/think/2015/10/01/vietnam-part-ii/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/think/2015/10/01/vietnam-part-ii/</guid>
        
        <category>think</category>
        
        
        <category>think</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Vietnam: Part I</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;3 weeks. 9 stops.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent the first 10 days mostly in cities, ranging from the non-stop craziness and heat of Saigon, to the peaceful, cooler, alps-like Dalat. My time in south and central Vietnam is characterized mostly by delicious, cheap food, heaps of energy, and a good dose of culture and history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Saigon (Ho Chi Minh City)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First stop in Vietnam, and immediately overwhelmed by the constant, never-stopping flow of mopeds and motorcycles. Something as simple and mundane as crossing the street suddenly became a whole new adventure. The only way to cross a street was to take the first step, walk at a constant velocity straight, and trust that bikes would swerve out of your predicted path. I visited the War Remants Museum, which was gut wrenchingly sad especially as an American. Other than that, I spent most of my time in Saigon walking around the city trying to soak up its hustle bustle energy, eating as much street food as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/partone/banhmi.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/partone/market.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/partone/war.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/partone/streets.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Dalat&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is there not to love about Dalat? When I arrived, the sun was setting, I was alone, and worst of all, quickly realizing I was lost. I wandered into a hotel looking for directions and discovered I was not a 5 minute walking distance from my hostel, but a 50 minute walk away. The older woman I was talking to immediately jumped up to help me, put my stuff on her scooter, and took me to where I was supposed to be without asking for any compensation. Besides &lt;a href=&quot;/du/2015/09/06/canyoning-in-dalat/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;canyoning&lt;/a&gt;, which is still one of the &lt;a href=&quot;/think/2015/09/22/best-of-vietnam/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;highlights&lt;/a&gt; of my time in Vietnam, I also went on a motorbike tour of the countryside, learning how silk, coffee, and rice wine are produced. Beautiful views combined with a cooler climate, an adorable family hostel, the best bakery I found in Vietnam, and especially great people makes Dalat my favorite city in southern Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/partone/farm.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/partone/fall.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/partone/coffee.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/partone/bakery.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Nha Trang&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had a 3 hour bus &quot;layover&quot; in this beach town so headed to the only thing there was to see - the beach. Worth mentioning only for the BEST &lt;i&gt;banh xeo&lt;/i&gt; I got on a random corner for less than a dollar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/partone/nhatrang.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/partone/banhxeo.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Hoi An&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After 16 hours on a bus, Hoi An was heaven. Rented a bicycle for the day and biked around the old city, and found my way to the beach. Charming and vintage-looking, with a market right along the river, colorful boats, and walking streets. Most photogenic city ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/partone/hoian.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/partone/river.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/partone/beach.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/partone/boats.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Hue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spent 2 days in Hue, which was more than enough. Highlight was the market, which was packed with good deals, cheap eats, and no tourists in sight. Also visited the DMZ (de-militarized zone) to learn more about the effects of the Vietnam War (or, the “American War” as they call it), and also their perception of America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/partone/hue.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/partone/citadel.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/partone/dmz.JPG&quot; height=&quot;600px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/think/2015/10/01/vietnam-part-i/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/think/2015/10/01/vietnam-part-i/</guid>
        
        <category>think</category>
        
        
        <category>think</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Best of Vietnam</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Dudes. I fell in love with this country.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With its vibrant energy, the organized chaos, the frenzied craziness of the locals (the Vietnamese are insane), stepping through swarms of motorbikes hoping you’d make it out unscathed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/highlights/streets.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Saigon at sunset.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the constantly changing yet consistently beautiful terrain, the diversity and richness of things to do and places to explore. Beaches, mountains, rice paddies, caves, jungles, waterfalls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With putting lime on all my noodles, hunting for the cheapest &lt;i&gt;banh mi&lt;/i&gt;, sipping on a perfect cup of coffee with condensed milk every morning (and afternoon…and evening…).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could &lt;i&gt;feel&lt;/i&gt; the life pulsing through the streets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/highlights/pho.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;A perfect bowl of pho.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;And I loved who I was while I was there.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more time I spent in Vietnam, the more I became consumed by it and by the backpacker lifestyle, the more I just &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;let. it. happen.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; In between adventuring, I’ll remember the countless rounds of pool, games of cards won and lost, bonds forged through stories swapped, mounds of inside jokes shared between groups from all over the world, happy hours that passed like minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I only have fond memories from my time there – to be honest, I’m even a little sad my visa expired and I’m already in Thailand. I’ll be catching up on blogging sometime soon, but for now, just some of my favorite moments from my time in Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Trip Highlights&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/highlights/canyon.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Abseiling down waterfalls and cliff jumping in Dalat.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/highlights/phongnha.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;800px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Absolutely everything about Phong Nha. Especially the Dark Cave.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/highlights/motorbike.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Learning how to motorbike on Cat Ba Island.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/highlights/sweet.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Trying the Cat Ba sweet, and getting an extra special treat.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/highlights/sapa.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Clouds and mountains and rice paddies and trekking in Sapa.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/vietnam/highlights/friend.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Meeting this goon. Travel buddy for 10 days, friend for life.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/think/2015/09/22/best-of-vietnam/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/think/2015/09/22/best-of-vietnam/</guid>
        
        <category>think</category>
        
        
        <category>think</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Canyoning in Dalat</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;&quot;Don&#39;t be lazy, get crazy!&quot;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s 7 AM, I’m in a white van with 9 people I just met, having been in Dalat for fewer than 11 hours, while 3 overly enthusiastic Vietnamese men shout that phrase at us. Multiple times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had arrived at my homestay the night before by sleeper bus from Ho Chi Minh city, and stumbled into a huge conversation about &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canyoning&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;canyoning&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;i&gt;&quot;You climb down waterfalls! You take a 11 m jump!&quot;&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;You have to do it! It&#39;s amazing!&quot;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Damn peer pressure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;i&gt;&quot;...yeah except the 11 m jump is a bit scarier, you have to clear about 1 m of rocks. You have to run otherwise you&#39;re done for.&quot;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Damn rocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;But after jumping off a &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/du/2015/06/28/a-216m-leap-of-faith/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;216 m bridge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;, how scary could a 11 m waterfall be?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/canyon/crew.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Cozy Nook crew (Katie, Ed, Theo, and I) with Tiger and Banana.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our group of 10, including 3 others from my homestay, scramble out of the van onto the side of a road about 20 minutes outside of the city, and then our energetic guides, Banana, Tree, and Tiger, help us put our equipment on: life jackets, harnesses, helmets, gloves…even knee pads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/canyon/group.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Full squad.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The adventure begins.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After trekking in the jungle for about 15 minutes, we arrive at a small waterfall (read: bump in the stream) and Tree stops us. First up is water sliding!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;i&gt;&quot;Ladies first!&quot;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tree grabs my hand, and although a little hesitant to be the first in the entire group, I say fuck it and go with him. I barely sit down before I feel Tree grabbing my ankles, rotating me, until I realize what’s happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wait, what, hey, feet first feet first!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m yelling, pleading, but it’s too late and I am being swept away by the water, head first, back to the unknown, unaware of what’s ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;And that&#39;s the genius of it, what makes the ride almost peaceful.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that you can’t see what’s ahead, there’s nothing distracting you, and all you can do is ride the feeling, the movement at &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; moment in time. You don’t know when you’ll plunge into the water, just that you will, and there’s no planning ahead or bracing yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a couple rounds (including some tandem sliding), our group moves on to abseiling – scaling down waterfalls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;i&gt;&quot;Ladies first!&quot;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tree gestures to me again. I’m beginning to see a pattern. Before I start scaling the waterfall, I get one heads up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;i&gt;&quot;You&#39;ll run out of rope, so you&#39;ll have to let go and fall the last 4 m.&quot;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I make my way down the waterfall fairly easily (woo!), until I run out of rope – as expected. Getting ready for my real life trust fall, I take a break from staring at the rock face, and look down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/canyon/waterfall.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Abseiling down the first waterfall.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Ha. There is &lt;i&gt;no&lt;/i&gt; way that is 4 m. There is absolutely no way.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look up at Tree, I look down at Tiger, I look back up at Tree, expecting them to contradict what I know is coming next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;i&gt;&quot;1, 2, 3!!&quot;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before my brain and body registers what is happening, I’ve pushed off the waterfall, let go of the rope, and have already landed in the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/canyon/falling.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Letting go. I do not remember this moment.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My landing is calm and still compared to the force of the waterfall, the water is shallow enough that I walk to shore to await the others. I watch over and over again, as each person reaches the end, as each person scoffs when it is their turn to trust, when it is their turn to fall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Before every jump is a bit of disbelief and doubt, a moment of hesitation, almost as if it&#39;s built into our very nature to be a bit skeptical, even when we know we&#39;ll be ok.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exact suspension of trust hit me the worst during the 11 m jump.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After abseiling, our group reaches a cliff, the one with a bit of rock jutting out. When it is my turn, I clarify and double check where I am supposed run, where I am supposed to jump, pacing from the starting point to the cliff multiple times. I muster up some mental energy, and think of Theo and Ed who just jumped before me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Finally, I think I&#39;m ready.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walk back, until I hit the tree, and I start jogging towards the edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1, 2, 3 steps, 4 steps, 5, 6, and then….I stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;My feet halt a few inches before my jump, and I turn around.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;i&gt;Shit.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banana puts down his camera with a concerned look on his face, encouraging, almost emphatic as he approaches me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;i&gt;&quot;Be strong! If you no strong, don&#39;t jump. Be mentally strong. Strong!&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I get it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I soon realize is that the &lt;b&gt;jump is not about the physical jump at all&lt;/b&gt;. Rather, it is a battle with your mind, and winning it requires you to first stop focusing on the physical, and tackle insecurity head on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;You become what you think you are.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you commit, if you think and tell yourself you’re going to clear the rocks until you believe it, you will; if you’re scared or hesitant, you won’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, we were all physically capable of clearing the 1 m of rocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The &lt;i&gt;only&lt;/i&gt; difference between those who attempted the jump and those who didn&#39;t, was mindset.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That thought really stuck with me, has still stuck with me, especially when I think of all the times when &lt;b&gt;we&lt;/b&gt; are the &lt;b&gt;only&lt;/b&gt; things that hold ourselves back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that, I walk back to the tree again, this time with a whole new approach. I fixate at the water in front of me and think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;I am strong. I am jumping. And yeah. I&#39;m making it.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/du/canyon/jump.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/du/2015/09/06/canyoning-in-dalat/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/du/2015/09/06/canyoning-in-dalat/</guid>
        
        <category>du</category>
        
        
        <category>du</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Snapshots of Cambodia</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Cambodia.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s got the chill beach vibes of south Thailand, the cultural vibes of Vietnam, and can still hold its own with its national relics – all without the high profile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You still got the drunk tourists on holiday (gap yah anyone?), restaurants serving Western food (why do I need a taco in Cambodia?), overpriced everything, and the beginnings of infrastructure built to cater to the influx of foreigners coming in (I have never used so many $1 bills).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there’s still the opportunity to see a piece of Cambodia that takes only a tad more time and effort to get to, the places where you gesture wildly because English is a bit of a struggle, where you’re staring at rice paddies more than buildings, and where the dirt on the countryside roads congeal into mud to make for a crazy motorbike ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wish I had more time to spend it in the latter and get off the beaten path, because Cambodia truly is a developing country on the brink of a tourism boom, with a rich legacy, open-hearted people, and a nostalgic sort of beauty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Trip Highlights&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/highlights/ATV.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Riding an ATV through the countryside of Siem Reap at sunset.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/highlights/sunrise.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Staying up until sunrise at the Full Moon Party on Koh Rong.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/highlights/explore.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:-10px;padding-bottom:20px&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Exploring temples at and near Angkor Wat.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Phnom Penh&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/phnompenh/paddy.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/phnompenh/tree.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/phnompenh/s21.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/phnompenh/nightmarket.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Sihanoukville&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/sihanoukville/sunset.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/sihanoukville/chillin.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Koh Rong&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/kohrong/boat.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/kohrong/beach.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Siem Reap&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/sr/angkor.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/sr/temple1.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/sr/temple2.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/sr/temple3.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/sr/temple4.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/sr/temple5.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/sr/temple6.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/sr/temple7.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/sr/temple8.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/sr/ricepaddy.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/sr/roads.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/sr/sunset.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;600px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Food&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/food/amok.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/food/noodles.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/food/thaicurry.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/food/bao.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/food/soup.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/img/think/cambodia/food/coco.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;375px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/think/2015/09/01/cambodia/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/think/2015/09/01/cambodia/</guid>
        
        <category>think</category>
        
        
        <category>think</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
