<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eat. Think. Du.</title>
    <description>Write your site description here. It will be used as your sites meta description as well!</description>
    <link>http://eatthinkdu.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://eatthinkdu.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 23:59:37 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 23:59:37 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>High Tea</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;I feel uncomfortable in fancy places.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everytime I go somewhere upscale I feel like I need to pack all of me into a tiny little pretty box, tuck all the ends in, smooth out any edges, and top everything off with a perfect, tidy bow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my mind this box is an easter shade of pastel pink. This bow is made of satin and is white, not off-white.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past week, I went to afternoon tea, or as described by Wikipedia, “a social event for the upper classes,” at Mount Nelson Hotel, one of the fanciest hotels in Cape Town. In the spirit of embracing new environments, I went. Plus, who can say no to an afternoon of unlimited finger foods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;And it was a ton of &lt;i&gt;fun&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/eat/tea/finger.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/eat/tea/zerts.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/eat/tea/boys.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/eat/tea/girls.JPG&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding:20px;display:inline-block&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;I guess there&#39;s an air of &lt;i&gt;innocence&lt;/i&gt; amongst a group of young 20 somethings sitting at high tea.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being excited over saying the word “booking.” Getting to use sugar cubes instead of sugar packets. Spilling 1/2 of a teapot of tea on your pants. Dripping jam on my dress and then trying to subtly lick it off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;I guess there&#39;s also an air of &lt;i&gt;privilege&lt;/i&gt; amongst a group of young 20 somethings sitting at high tea.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left feeling slightly guilty. And it was more than the fact that I literally ate my weight’s worth in clotted cream and jam which was probably going to give me both diabetes and heart disease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here in Cape Town, where the disparity in wealth is so great and so starkly obvious, it made me slightly guilty to know that a person from a point of privilege like myself could easily and happily spend R270 ($25) on a buffet of tea, finger foods, and mini desserts, while right outside the door the homeless begged for R10 (less than $1) worth of bread. I’ve spent a large portion of my blog talking about the fun things I’ve been able to do, the incredible views I’ve been able to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;But the reality is that there remain a lot of issues that run deep in Cape Town&#39;s veins.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unemployment is a big one. Poverty, and especially poverty in the townships, is another. Racial tensions seem to only exacerbate these existing problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From an outsider’s perspective (not saying this is true, just saying this is how I feel), it sometimes feels like these issues are swept under the facade of a hip, beautiful city trying to prove itself, trying to recover from a not-so-distant, painfully bitter past. Because Cape Town is fairly well developed and resembles a scenic European city by the water, it’s so &lt;b&gt;easy&lt;/b&gt; for tourists to purposefully or accidentally or blissfully ignore the massive disparity in wealth that exists in and around this city. In this country. In this continent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;And to be completely honest, as an American just visiting for a few months, I still don&#39;t know how to respond.&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://eatthinkdu.com/eat/2015/07/23/high-tea/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eatthinkdu.com/eat/2015/07/23/high-tea/</guid>
        
        <category>eat</category>
        
        
        <category>eat</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>At the Edge of the World</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Admitting our limits, and that we have limits, is an exercise in humility.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Realizing that humanity itself has limits, and seeing those limits, was that, but at a whole different magnitude. Today, and only for a moment, I looked over a cliff, saw nothing but ocean crashing into mountains melding into sky, and felt like I was seeing the edge of existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were overlooking the water at the southwestern most tip of Africa after having scrambled up some rocks when the thought crossed my mind that the next land mass over was Antarctica and it felt strange to me how the world suddenly seemed so confined. The thought should have been obvious and insignificant, but to me it was neither of those things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our crew headed out early to drive south along a scenic coastline to Cape Point, and lastly, Cape of Good Hope, stopping along some view points along the way. It still surprises me how the mountains never fail to impress me, and that a beautiful sunset or a massive cliff of rocks next to water never gets old. Besides being blessed with incredible T-shirt weather, it was a fun day of exploring, exotic animals, and being impressed by nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/du/cape/cape1.JPG&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/du/cape/cape2.JPG&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/du/cape/cape3.JPG&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/du/cape/cape4.JPG&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/du/cape/cape5.JPG&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/du/cape/cape6.JPG&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/du/cape/cape7.JPG&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://eatthinkdu.com/du/2015/07/19/cape-point/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eatthinkdu.com/du/2015/07/19/cape-point/</guid>
        
        <category>du</category>
        
        
        <category>du</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Garden Route</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;I just had the most incredible weekend.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of friends, of fun, of adventure, memories for a lifetime, being young and being reckless. Feeling close without actually being close, but just enjoying each other’s company and travelling together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a month ago we were just a collection of strangers, but we had stumbled into maybe, probably, definitely too much bonding, and whether we wanted to or not, had become an iX family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weekend was packed with scheduled activities, from visiting caves to riding ostriches, but my favorite moments were the times when we were driving, just staring out the window looking out across the changing landscape the sunset with the mountains and the colors the clouds the trees. Those were the times when the thought crossed my mind that things could not possibly get better than this, that this was perfection and just the act of &lt;b&gt;being&lt;/b&gt; was enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who don’t like to read, I made a video of all the pictures I took. For everyone else, read on for the sparknotes version of the weekend. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OnX0J9it8Uc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Ostrich Riding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/du/gardenroute/ostrich.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, it might be safe to say that ostriches are probably the dumbest animals known to man. Look at their heads, there is actually physically no room for a brain. Second, ostriches are definitely not meant to be ridden, and it was one of the funniest things to witness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Animal Sanctuary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/du/gardenroute/cheetah.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though the animal sanctuary was a bit like a glorified zoo, I’m not gonna lie, getting to pet a cheetah was simultaneously so against nature, and also the coolest thing ever. These animals are running, hunting machines. Now domesticated in your nearest South African resrve so that hoards of Americans can snuggle it and snap selfies. Tourism at its finest or most ridiculous?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Backpackers Hostel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/du/gardenroute/hostel.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our drive up to our hostel by the beach was idealistic like no other, with the sun setting, ocean to our right, and the mist and clouds just hitting the mountains. A bunch of us decided to head to the beach for a night swim, and it really did feel like we were just a bunch of little kids and the beach was our giant sandbox and the ocean was our kiddie pool. The next day we found out a surfer lost his leg to a shark in the &lt;i&gt;next bay over&lt;/i&gt;. Go figure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Rastafarian Community Tour&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/du/gardenroute/rasta.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Epic trip with an even more epic tour guide (shoutout to brother Zeb). Totally vibing with the culture and the music. Peace, love, and fun grass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Elephant Riding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/du/gardenroute/elephant.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elephants are just incredibly adorable creatures, and riding off into the sunset with elephants in South Africa held twangs of surrealism, nostalgia, and cheesy tourist vibes. They always look like they’re smiling. Not sure if other animals really compete there. The count of number of animals we rode that weren’t meant to be ridden goes up by 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Bungee Jumping&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/du/gardenroute/bungee.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So cool I had to write a separate post about it &lt;a href=&quot;/du/2015/06/28/a-216m-leap-of-faith/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Game Drive&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/du/gardenroute/game.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE&lt;/strong&gt; safari experience, mini edition. We took a open top 4x4 and saw a whole lot of animals. Highlights include perhaps the best tour guide in the world, Leroy, getting close to the lions without dying, and witnessing a carcass recently torn up by a cheetah.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://eatthinkdu.com/du/2015/06/29/garden-route/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eatthinkdu.com/du/2015/06/29/garden-route/</guid>
        
        <category>du</category>
        
        
        <category>du</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A 216m Leap of Faith</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;What is your biggest fear?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it dying? Is death the worst thing that can happen to you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be completely honest, I can think of a few things that scare me &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; than death. Losing all your memories and your personality. Losing your mind. Being in a coma and not being able to wake up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not saying I don’t fear death because I do. And heights. Rejection. Loneliness. Failure. I would be lying if I said these things don’t scare me because they &lt;i&gt;absolutely&lt;/i&gt; do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Maybe they even scare you too.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that I’m trying to do with my time off is to face my fears. Usually this leads to me doing questionable or stupid shit, but I think that comes with taking risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think you ever get rid of fear, nor would you want to. That pit in your gut, that flutter in your stomach – those are instincts that keep you alive. It’s not so much about “overcoming” your fears as much as it is about doing despite them, continuing through those moments of uncertainty, the blanched face, the almost-shitting-your-pants, about-to-scream-oh-wait-already-screaming moments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fear is 100% about admitting that you are 100% not ok, so that courage can be the leap of faith that follows. And that faith is the most incredible feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;I took a literal leap of faith today.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A 216m leap to be exact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our group woke up at 7 am to make our 9 am bungee reseravation, and the minute I got off the bus, a hoard of conflicting thoughts were already racing through my brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t want to die.” 
“But I won’t.”
“Trust engineering.”
“Except for those times when engineers fucked up, that’s no good.”
“But wait, this is going to be incredible.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be completely honest, walking from the base to the middle of the bridge was already terrifying. I was walking so slowly I actually apologized to my friend behind me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re up on that ledge, standing, looking over and you just see for miles. In all directions. Including down. Ok so that’s a stretch, but at that moment, you are completely preoccupied with what is happening below, and you can’t help but realize that it’s all trees, valley, which translates to no cushioning if something goes awry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The staff gave me a quick countdown: “3, 2, 1, bungee!” My feet pushed off and I tried to throw my body as far horizontally as I could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;For 2 seconds, my life seemed over.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stomach drops head rush lungs yelling screaming. Well that was dumb. You become instantly aware of how fragile we all are and for a split second you think you’ve made a huge mistake jumping off that bridge because yes you’re going to die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But just as soon as it starts, it’s over. And just as the screaming ends, an amazing rush also takes over and doesn’t let go of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt; The rush is indescribable.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I’m going to do a bad job at explaining it. It’s like a combination of your brain exploding in the best way, having all your senses filled up all at once, and your internal organs having a dance party inside of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;And you are fucking flying.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The laughter started quickly after the jump and didn’t let go of me. I’m not even sure where it stemmed from. But it’s an uncontrollable laughter, laughing because you cheated death and gravity, and because your body doesn’t know how to react besides being thankful that you are safe, so it bursts into a fit of undeniable happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;I was just so grateful to be alive.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Completely amped on life, ready to go out, take on the world, feeling invincible. Best natural high I’ve felt in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;It&#39;s strange to think that all these things were made possible by fear.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not the absence of fear, but the complete presence of fear, and having the complete faith to confront it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://eatthinkdu.com/du/2015/06/28/a-216m-leap-of-faith/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eatthinkdu.com/du/2015/06/28/a-216m-leap-of-faith/</guid>
        
        <category>du</category>
        
        
        <category>du</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Old Biscuit Mill</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;If you&#39;ve ever tried to go out to eat with me, you know that I am the worst decider ever.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not that I’m a picky eater. Because I will eat virtually anything and everything in front of me. It’s actually the opposite. Whenever I get a menu, I’m completely overwhelmed by all the choices that &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; potentially make me happy that I get confused about what will make me the &lt;em&gt;happiest&lt;/em&gt;, and end up taking forever to decide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is usually how a typical dinner goes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Look at menu&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Freak out at the first thing that looks good&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Look down the page and realize you get the same feeling looking at half the menu&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enter into life dilemma mode and become extremely focused, debating between at minimum 3 options&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When waiter comes, ask for his or her recommendation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He or she usually says the wrong thing, completely ignore 2-3 recommendations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Order something completely different from original choices and recommendations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ignore friends&#39; exasperated expressions and feel sense of pride for making a decision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;That&#39;s kind of why I love food markets.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can grab tiny things to eat along the way, and get a little bit of everything. No commitment to a large portion, ability to maximize awesomeness. There are a ton of different food markets all over Cape Town, almost every weekend, some of them weekly, some of them seasonal, some of the for special occasions and festivals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Saturday, I went to &lt;b&gt;Old Biscuit Mill&lt;/b&gt; in Woodstock, an artsy neighborhood with chill vibes where hippies, artists, and reggae performers hang.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Old Biscuit Mill had some serious eats -- everything from potato latkes to dim sum to ginger shots...&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/eat/biscuit/market.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Walking through the market
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/eat/biscuit/benedict.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    THE BEST
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/eat/biscuit/mushrooms.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Delicious mushroom kebabs
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/eat/biscuit/paella.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Smells like Spain
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/eat/biscuit/sangria.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Drinks like Spain too
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/eat/biscuit/dimsum.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Taste of Asia?
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/eat/biscuit/bakery.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Artisan bakers
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/eat/biscuit/kosher.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Healthy yums
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;...and also some serious vibes. LIVE MUSIC and a flea market.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GtjP1eWgTlE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;So yes, I &lt;i&gt;still&lt;/i&gt; suck at deciding. Which at Old Biscuit Mill, turned out to be both a blessing and a curse.&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://eatthinkdu.com/eat/2015/06/20/old-biscuit-mill/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eatthinkdu.com/eat/2015/06/20/old-biscuit-mill/</guid>
        
        <category>eat</category>
        
        
        <category>eat</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Change of Pace</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;If Cape Town is living a million miles a minute, Stellenbosch is straight up ambling.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stayed behind after the Spice Route tour to spend the weekend with Emily, who is interning in Stellenbosch for the summer. Stellenbosch was definitely a smaller town – not many cars, few people, even fewer beggars. The town seemed predominantly Afrikaans, and it was the first time in South Africa where I was in situations where I couldn’t understand what was going on around me. All in all, it was a well needed break from the fast life with iXperience in Cape Town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Highlights of the trip include:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;beautiful countryside scenery&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;everything was way cheaper. I mean, R5 ice cream, come on&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;better service and an adorably nice waiter at a great steak restaurant&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a real apartment with a real room and a real kitchen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;quiet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;getting to see Emily!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;At the end of the day though, there&#39;s no place I&#39;d rather be than Cape Town :)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/stellenbosch/emily.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Visiting my beautiful little little little twin star Emily!
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/stellenbosch/scenery.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    During our hike.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/stellenbosch/erica.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Happy and grateful for that change in pace.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://eatthinkdu.com/du/2015/06/15/change-of-pace/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eatthinkdu.com/du/2015/06/15/change-of-pace/</guid>
        
        <category>du</category>
        
        
        <category>du</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I Have Truly Found Paradise</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;I have truly found paradise.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And not the kind of IHTFP from MIT, none of that. This past weekend we went wine tasting at a gem called Spice Route. Spice Route is basically a collection of artisan food and drink merchants situated on a beautiful farm near Stellenbosch, with awesome chocolate, wine, beer, cheese, biltong, gelato, and art. Did I mention that the chocolate was amazing. Because it was. Seriously the only thing this place is missing to become perfection is puppies. And maybe crepes. I was disappointed that I couldn’t find crepes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started out with a white and red wine tasting, paired with 5 different types of chocolate, and then moved on to beer paired with a biltong and cheese sampler. Even though it’s technically winter here in South Africa, it was really sunny, and the leaves were still falling, kind of like how it would look on a perfect fall day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Here&#39;s a peek into my heaven on earth.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/eat/spice/scenery.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    That background scenery doe, in the midst of beautiful wine country.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/eat/spice/signs.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    All of these things are my favorites.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/eat/spice/path.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Walking through on a beautiful fall day.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/eat/spice/wine.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Wine AND chocolate!
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/eat/spice/chocolate.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Just straight up chocolate.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/eat/spice/biltong_cheese.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Biltong AND cheese!
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/eat/spice/art_barn.jpg&quot; height=&quot;400px&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Art barn at the end of the route.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://eatthinkdu.com/eat/2015/06/14/ihtfp/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eatthinkdu.com/eat/2015/06/14/ihtfp/</guid>
        
        <category>eat</category>
        
        
        <category>eat</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Hard Stuff</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;The first month is always hard.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first day I was in Spain, I got dropped off on a random street corner, almost got kicked out of my apartment on hour 1 due to a payment misunderstanding. When jokes get repeated 10 times for a foreigner who still has no clue what’s being said, they are no longer funny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first month I was in NYC, I legitimately contemplated buying a ticket out to SF for the weekend. Let’s just say that the cramped space, coupled with the undeniable episode of bedbugs drove me to cheapflights.com at 4 am in the morning many a night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who would’ve guessed that those two summers turned out to be the best in my life? Somehow it happened, it always does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;So, it really didn&#39;t surprise me at all when I started to have bouts of blues here in Cape Town.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It really does surprise me how &lt;i&gt;infrequently&lt;/i&gt; I feel uncomfortable here. How easy it was to build relationships and form new attachments. It almost bothers me how quickly this new &lt;i&gt;lifestyle&lt;/i&gt; has fallen into place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, the first month is always hard, and these are the things I miss the most, some more serious than others:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;5. Electricity...all the time.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People. Loadshedding is a thing. For everyone not in South Africa, please look it up RIGHT NOW. This is important. This is what &lt;i&gt;actually&lt;/i&gt; happens. The government just turns off electricity for huge areas at a time. Why is the rest of the world not talking about this?? How is this ok?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;4. Summer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok to be perfectly clear, I admit, “winter” here is a complete joke. 60 degree weather is spring or fall at best. Everytime some complains about the cold, I seriously want to call the wah-bulance. But as I’m finding out, without central heating, winter here does not joke around. It gets a bit nippy when the sun’s not out. Why am I wearing a jacket? It’s supposed to be June? This is not helping my self-diagnosed Seasonal Affective Disorder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;3. Dollars&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look up the Dollar to Rand conversion rate. Realize that I am being paid in Rand. Look over at MIT degrees already gathering dust and angry emails from parents. Rinse. Repeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;2. Free Time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one’s sort of a joke, since I never got free time at MIT either. But people tell me about this thing called free time, and it seems incredible. Like you get to do stuff you like that’s not work. WHOA! It sounds nice in theory yeah? Maybe one of these days I’ll figure out this whole balance thing and I’ll try it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;1. Being able to reference inside jokes from last year. Looking at your friend and knowing that something&#39;s up...and vice versa.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s just something nice about reminicising about the good old times. This one’s a shoutout to you my B5 Bros, my MIT family, and Tonka crew. Time isn’t the most important part of friendship, but does a helluva good job when it comes to staying power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And even though I’m probably having the most incredible experience of my life, have met some people I genuinely call my friends…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;I really do still miss you guys. Is that too much?&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://eatthinkdu.com/think/2015/06/11/the-hard-stuff/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eatthinkdu.com/think/2015/06/11/the-hard-stuff/</guid>
        
        <category>think</category>
        
        
        <category>think</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Unreal Reality</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;I am living an unreal reality, and I&#39;m just waiting to wake up from a dream.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My boss asked me the other day, “If you could describe your experience here in Cape Town, what would it be?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&quot;What is going on, who am I?&quot;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things are coming at me a million miles a minute, a different sort of firehose, and I am saying yes to everything. I have no idea who this version of myself is, but she is way crazier than the actual Erica. She is also pretty awesome. Maybe I like it. I can’t tell yet. You be the judge – here’s a handful of things I’ve been able to do while in Cape Town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;secion-heading&quot;&gt;Shark Cage Diving&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/shark.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s exactly what it sounds like, I got to go diving with Great Whites my first weekend in Cape Town. What no one tells you: you wake up at 4 am in the morning, and then board a boat where 25% of the people will barf multiple times. Another 25% will feel like they could chunder at any given moment but hold back by staring at land or sucking on a lollipop. Go figure. What you probably guessed: it was a f***ing awesome experience. Sharks are beautiful. Not to mention massive. You need to do it. Would not recommend drinking the night before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;secion-heading&quot;&gt;Surfing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/surfing.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every once in a while, I need an experience that knocks me on the ground so I can get back up again (am I masochistic?). Surfing is exactly that. Literally, exactly that. Even though I’ve wakeboarded and snow boarded before, surfing kicked my ass, and I loved it. There is nothing cooler than standing up on top of a wave, and then getting sucked back into ocean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;secion-heading&quot;&gt;Sandboarding&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://eatthinkdu.com/img/sand-min.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; style=&quot;padding-top:20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I distinctly remember lying on the sand next to a friend, board in hand, thinking out loud, “Does it get any better than this?” Can’t decide what was more fun: sandboarding, running around barefoot with new friends, sliding down sand hills, holding on for life on the back of a pick up truck driving around the dunes. Current vote is for the running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;secion-heading&quot;&gt;Nightlife&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weekends in Cape Town have been something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;This is my new normal.&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://eatthinkdu.com/du/2015/06/07/unreal-reality/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eatthinkdu.com/du/2015/06/07/unreal-reality/</guid>
        
        <category>du</category>
        
        
        <category>du</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I landed in Cape Town</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;I am exhausted.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the type of exhausted where you’re not only physically tired, but also drained socially and mentally, enough so that not even sleep or massive amounts of coffee will cut it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I flew to Cape Town 3 days after frantically turning in my Master’s thesis, 2 days after a farewell party to say goodbye to all my friends, 1 day after packing up all my things from 5 years in Boston and shipping said boxes to MN, and a couple of hours after packing my suitcases for my 6 months abroad. I &lt;del&gt;think&lt;/del&gt; know I have to be crazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even crazier? The amount of things that have happened in such a short span of time. I don’t even have the time or energy to put all my thoughts into words right now. But I landed in Cape Town a week ago…and here’s what happened next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6Gn0ryGjzPU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://eatthinkdu.com/du/2015/05/27/i-landed-in-cape-town/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eatthinkdu.com/du/2015/05/27/i-landed-in-cape-town/</guid>
        
        <category>du</category>
        
        
        <category>du</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
